Guide to the Andrew Dickson White papers, 1832-1919.
White, Andrew Dickson papers, 1832-1919
- Series VIII. Pamphlets and booklets
  - Published in the U.S.
    - New York State Local History Leaflets. Verrazano's Voyage Along the Atlantic Coast of North America., 1917 (Box 231, Folder 12)
    - H.S. Perris, The War as viewed by a Liberal Englishman., 1917 (Box 231, Folder 13)
    - Chapters reprinted from The Romanic Review., 1914 (Box 231, Folder 13)
    - Donald McFayden, "An Apology for the Church's Persecution of Science" reprinted from University of Colorado Studies., 1914 (Box 231, Folder 13)
    - The Messenger., March, 1904 (Box 231, Folder 13)
    - Preserved Smith, Luther's Development of the Doctrine of Justification by Faith Only., 1913 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - Case and Comment., November, 1914 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - El Pensamiento Contemporaneo., June, 1892 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - Proceedings of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution, with statement., 1906 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - Yale Class Records (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - West Publishing Co's Docket., April-May, 1910 (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - Loose clippings (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - Masaccio. (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - The Second Annual Report of the Public Schools of Binghamton., 1881 (Box 231, Folder 16)
    - Message of John W. Hoyt., 1882 (Box 231, Folder 16)
    - Banquet Adresses for the order of the Founders and Patriots of America (Box 231, Folder 16)
    - The English Benedictines and Their Bishops in the Thirteenth Century. (Box 231, Folder 16)
    - The World Court., January, 1917 (Box 231, Folder 17)
    - George Hamilton, The DEscendants of Ganelon and of Others., 1919 (Box 231, Folder 17)
    - Proceedings of the North Central History Teachers' Association., 1908 (Box 231, Folder 17)
    - The Review of Reviews., August, 1892 (Box 231, Folder 17)
    - James M. Pryse, The Apocalypse Unsealed review (Box 231, Folder 17)
  - European and South American Publishers
    - Alliance des Femmes Orientales et Occidentales., 1903 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Shore Excursion: Venezuela., 1907 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Die Nation., 1902 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Revue Scientifique., 1863 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Theologische Rundschau., 1915 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Die Woche., 1902 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Sonder-Abdruck aus dem Theologischen Jahresbericht. (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Duty of the United States in Cuba., 1906 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - El Protectorado., 1907 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Quellen und Darstellungen aus der Geschichte des Reformationjahrhunderts., 1908 (Box 231, Folder 9)
  - Catalogues
    Many contain annotations an purchase information.
    - Verseichniss für Unterrichts-Modelle, Apparate und Instrumente Jeder Art. (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Kunst-Verlag Fritz Gurlitt. (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Literatur und Kunstgeschichte: Antiquarischer Katalog von Heinrich Kerler., 1887 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - K.F. Koehler's Antiquarium Katalog., 1887 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Lager-Katalog von Richard Bertling in Dresden., 1888 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Katalog von Theodor Ackermann., 1889 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Rudolf Merkel: Buchhandlung und Antiquariat in Erlangen., 1889 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Bücher-Verzeichniss von Trübner's Buchhandlung und Antiquariat., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Three catalogues of Joseph Baer, Frankfurt am main., 1890-1891 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - J. Scheible's Antiquariat und Verlagsbuchhandlung in Stuttgart., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Büucher-Verzeichnik von Ferdinand Steinkopf., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Max Weg:L Buchhandlung und Antiquariat., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Antiquariats-Catalog von Paul Neubner., 1891 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Verzeichniss des Antiquarischen Büucherlagers von M. Spirgatis., 1891 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Catalogue de Livres Anciens chez Nicolas Scheuring., 1889 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Liberia Antiquaria Ermanno Loescher di Carlo Clausen., 1888 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Minerva., 1901 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Librairie J.B. Balliere et Fils. (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Catalogue de la Librairie Ancienne de Adolphe Geering., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - Livres Rares et Curieux...de A. Claudin., 1889, 1890 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Livres d'Occasion Rares et Curieux...a la Librarie Baillieu., 1889 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Ritchie's Catalogue of Philosophical Apparatus., 1868 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of Valuable Philosophical Apparatis...Charles N. Bancker, Esq.. (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - The Springfield Gas Machine., 1872 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Mann's Bone Cutter for Poultry Food., 1892 (Box 231, Folder 23)
    - The Map of Europe. (Box 231, Folder 23)
    - War Echoes., 1915 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - The Caxton Head Catalogue., January, April 1891 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - A Catalogue of Old, Rare, and Curious Books...selected from the stock of George Littlefield., 1891 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Arundel Society, Temperance and Justice. (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of Autographs, Family Histories, Heraldic and Interesting Collections...of T.C. Noble., 1891 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of Choice Literature...by John Grant., 1890 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - J. Salkeld's Special Clearance Catalogue., 1891 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - David Nutt's catalogue of Second-hand Books. (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of Second-hand Books...by U. Maggs. (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of Occult Literature...by Bertram Dobell. (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - A Catalogue of leading books on Egypt and Egyptology, and on Assyria and Assyriology. Trubner and Co.., 1881 (Box 231, Folder 22)
- Series IX. Objects and memorabilia
  - Information on previous silver storage methods, Undated (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - Card mentioning original locations of certain MU items (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - Silver chalices, Undated; MU-1935-1936 (Box 247)
  - Silver bowl with two handles, Undated; MU-1937 (Box 247)
  - Small silver pitcher, Undated; MU-1938 (Box 247)
  - Silver bowl with lid and two handles, Expression; MU-1939 (Box 247)
    Engraving: Clara D. White 1847; A. and F. from A.D.W. Jan. 6, 1884. Forms a set with MU-1940, MU-1984
  - Silver teapot with lid, 1847; MU-1940 (Box 247)
    Engraving: Clara D. White 1847; A. and F. from A.D.W. Jan. 6, 1884. Forms a set with MU-1939, MU-1984
  - Silver tourine and lid, 1898; MU-1941 (Box 248)
    Engraving: Andrew Dickson White, Ambassador of the United States, Berlin
  - Silver lorgnette with silver and pearl chain, Undated; MU-1942 (Box 249)
    Possibly belonged to Helen Magill White
  - Silver serving spoon, Undated; MU-1943 (Box 249)
    Engraving: HW
  - Two silver serving spoons, Undated; MU-1944 (Box 249)
    Engraving: Merrill, 1865-1890
  - Miami Biscayne Bay Florida spoon, Undated; MU-1945 (Box 249)
  - Trinidad spoon, Undated; MU-1946 (Box 249)
  - New York spoon, Undated; MU-1947 (Box 249)
  - Silver spoon, Undated; MU-1948 (Box 249)
    Engraving: Merrill
  - Spoon with cathedral design, Undated; MU-1949 (Box 249)
  - Silver spoon shaped like a geisha with a parasol, Undated; MU-1950 (Box 249)
  - 12 ivory or bone-handled knives with ornate engravings on blades, Undated; MU-1951 (Box 249)
    Forms a set with MU-1952
  - 12 ivory or bone-handled forks, Undated; MU-1952 (Box 249)
    Forms a set with MU-1951
  - Decorative silver spoon, Undated; MU-1953 (Box 249)
    Engraving: HM, Sept. 10, 1890 (a wedding gift)
  - Silver sugar sifter spoon, Undated; MU-1954 (Box 249)
  - 36 large silver forks, Undated; MU-1955 (Box 249)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1956, 1973
  - 6 large silver spoons, Undated; MU-1956 (Box 249)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1955, 1973
  - 6 silver knives with woven handle design, Undated; MU-1957 (Box 250)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1957, 1958
  - 6 silver forks with woven handle design, Undated; MU-1958 (Box 250)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1956, 1958
  - 6 silver spoons with woven handle design, Undated; MU-1959 (Box 250)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1956, 1957
  - Small silver tongs, Undated; MU-1960 (Box 250)
  - 6 silver spoons, Undated; MU-1961 (Box 250)
    Engraving: R
  - 3 silver spoons, Undated; MU-1962 (Box 250)
  - 24 silver and gold forks, Undated; MU-1963 (Box 250)
  - Fork with scene on handle, Undated; MU-1964 (Box 250)
  - 12 silver forks, Undated; MU-1965 (Box 250)
  - Silver and gold spoon with flower handle, Undated; MU-1966 (Box 250)
  - Silver serving fork, Undated; MU-1967 (Box 250)
  - Decorative silver spoon with image of St. Olaf, Undated; MU-1968 (Box 250)
  - 6 silver forks, Undated; MU-1969 (Box 250)
  - 8 silver two-tined forks, Undated; MU-1970 (Box 250)
  - 6 silver butter knives, Undated; MU-1971 (Box 250)
    Engraving: either MSM or WSW
  - 6 small silver butter knives, Undated; MU-1972 (Box 250)
  - 30 large knives, Undated; MU-1973 (Box 250)
    Engraving: W. Forms a set with MU-1955, 1956
  - Large silver ladle, Undated; MU-1974 (Box 251)
    Engraving: HM
  - Large silver ladle, Undated; MU-1975 (Box 251)
    Engraving: HM from LM
  - Silver candlestick, Undated; MU-1976 (Box 251)
    Given to Karin White by ADW on her sixth birthday
  - Silver vases, Undated; MU-1977-1978 (Box 251)
  - Marble paperweight with bronze winged lion, Undated; MU-1979 (Box 251)
  - Silver chalice/bowl, 1852; MU-1980 (Box 251)
    Engraving: Horace White 1852; A dn F from ADW Jan 6, 1884
  - Candlestick, Undated; MU-1981 (Box 252)
    Bronze winged woman sitting
  - Napoleon death mask brass and bronze inkwell, Undated; MU-1982 (Box 252)
  - Russian wine ladle, Undated; MU-1983 (Box 252)
    Engraving: ADW St. Petersburg 1892
  - Silver teapot with lid, ivory on handle, Undated; MU-1984 (Box 252)
    Engraving: Clara D. White 1847; A. and F. from A.D.W. Jan. 6, 1884. Forms a set with MU-1939, MU-1940
  - Gold wedding band, Undated; MU-1985
    Engraving: ADW-HM Sept. 10, 1890
  - Decorative wood and silver pipe, Undated; MU-2397 (Box 253)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
A. D. White, The Warfare of Science, 1876. Gifted to W.C. Gannett, with letter from White to Gannett
Henry C. Lea, Superstition and Force, 1866. With notes by White in front and back.
A.D. White, The First Hague Conference, reprinted from White's autobiography, 1912.
The Book of Common Prayer, given to Helen Magill from her mother, 1878.
John Lord, A Modern History, 1849. Used by White as a student at the University of Michigan and later as a professor.
The New Testament, 1881. Signed by White.
Nuovo Testamento, 1875. Signed by White, 1877.
S.C. Hall, ed. The Book of British Ballads, 1847. Presented to White by President Woolsey of Yale College, for winning a competition in composition. Inscription by White on inside cover.
Les Caractere de Theophraste, 1860. Charred book found among the ruins of St. Pierre, Martinique, after the eruption of Mt. Pelee in 1902. Given to the library by White in 1907.
James O. Carr, Esq, The Dickson Letters, 1901.